<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kishan Sampat</title><link href="https://kishansampat.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://kishansampat.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://kishansampat.github.io/</id><updated>2020-06-26T15:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Setting up a blog on Github</title><link href="https://kishansampat.github.io/blog-setup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-26T15:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-26T15:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Kishan Sampat</name></author><id>tag:kishansampat.github.io,2020-06-26:/blog-setup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A blog to note down your learnings on&amp;nbsp;Github&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Blogging can be a great way to take notes on your learnings. It&amp;#8217;s like taking notes in a class when you were in college. I find it easier to remember things when I write them down. I was suggested to use &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; as it is quite simple to deploy, and is also written in Python. This will further help me accelerate my Python learning. I will describe below on how to set up Pelican on your environment and start blogging away.&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found Pelican&amp;#8217;s setup documentation to be somewhat inadequate at explaining the full setup, so I also used a couple of sites to get the blog going. I used a combination of&lt;br&gt;
these sites: &lt;a href="https://rsip22.github.io/blog/create-a-blog-with-pelican-and-github-pages.html"&gt;Renata&amp;#8217;s Blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.dataquest.io/blog/how-to-setup-a-data-science-blog/"&gt;Dataquest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href="https://blog.justalfred.com/getting-started-with-pelican-on-github-pages.html"&gt;Just Alfred&lt;/a&gt;. While all of them have different approaches to how your setup should be, the initial setup is common amongst them, and I used what was best suited for me. It is not necessary that you follow the setup as below, and you can feel free to use your own combination or suggest a better one (I&amp;#8217;m always happy to receive feedback!)&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting up your Github Repo&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8212;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, it is good practice to host your blog on Github. It&amp;#8217;s free, easy and quick to set up. You can follow the instructions on the &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/en/github/getting-started-with-github/create-a-repo"&gt;Github Help Page&lt;/a&gt; to set it up. For your blog name, I&amp;#8217;d recommend starting with your own name, for example, I set up mine as [kishansampat.github.io]: https://kishansampat.github.io&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as mentioned in [Renata&amp;#8217;s Blog]: https://rsip22.github.io/blog/create-a-blog-with-pelican-and-github-pages.html &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/en/github/getting-started-with-github/create-a-repo"&gt;Github Help Page&lt;/a&gt;, it is recommended to initialize the reprository with a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt; and a free software license, so that you still own the code, but you make sure that others will also benefit from it, by allowing them to study it, reuse it and share&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Learning Path"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting your environment ready</title><link href="https://kishansampat.github.io/getting-ready.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-14T16:50:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-14T16:50:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Kishan Sampat</name></author><id>tag:kishansampat.github.io,2020-06-14:/getting-ready.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Getting the local enviroment ready on your&amp;nbsp;computer&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Once you have set up Ubuntu in VirtualBox, the next steps are to install Python, a text editor and any other personal software that you may require for your learning. To begin with, Python and a text editor should suffice. &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of text editors out there, and one could get easily confused with the choices available. I reached out to some of my colleagues for recommendations; &lt;a href="https://www.sublimetext.com"&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com"&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be the general recommendations for beginners. Note that for Windows, you can download the .exe installation files, however, for Ubuntu, you can install them directly via the terminal using sudo commands. You can simply search on Google and you&amp;#8217;d be able to find tons of instructions out there on how to do this. &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Python, Ubuntu already comes with a version of Python installed, however, it is best to have the latest one installed. I&amp;#8217;d recommend installing it in a Virtual Environment within your working folders. I&amp;#8217;ll come to that a bit later, once we&amp;#8217;ve started working on some code.&amp;nbsp;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you also need to install git on your machine. On Ubuntu, you can simply run the following command in your terminal: &lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install git-all&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Learning Path"></category><category term="environment setup"></category></entry><entry><title>Intro to my travel blog</title><link href="https://kishansampat.github.io/trvl-intro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-21T22:45:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-21T22:45:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Kishan Sampat</name></author><id>tag:kishansampat.github.io,2020-05-21:/trvl-intro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A brief intoduction to my travel&amp;nbsp;blog&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love traveling! (who doesn&amp;#8217;t?). This blog is a brief collection of memories from my travels. You&amp;#8217;ll mostly find &amp;#8220;how-to-do&amp;#8221; / &amp;#8220;what-to-do&amp;#8221; information in my blog. I love giving directions and telling people about how they could spend their time at a destination and how they could could do it, like navigating through public transportation or finding off the path restaurants, or simply finding those beautiful spots where one could just sit and enjoy the beauty of the place they are in! &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you find this information helpful, and get inspired to travel to these beautiful&amp;nbsp;destinations!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Travel Blog"></category><category term="travel blog intro"></category></entry><entry><title>Setting up your environment</title><link href="https://kishansampat.github.io/env-setup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-18T22:07:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-18T22:07:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Kishan Sampat</name></author><id>tag:kishansampat.github.io,2020-05-18:/env-setup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Setting up the local enviroment on your&amp;nbsp;computer&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a Windows 10 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;16GB&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;500GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSD&lt;/span&gt; Hard Disk. I was keen to initally try setting up my environment in Windows, however, I faced a number of errors just trying to get Python installed. &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is not impossible to get your environment set up on Windows, as a beginner, I decided to go with a VirtualBox setup and installed Ubuntu in it. My &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; has enough processing power, and it was proving to be a significant overhead to try and get Python installed; I thought it was better to go with an Ubuntu setup as I also found instructions on the web much easier to follow for Ubuntu. &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed VirtualBox and gave it about half of my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; (around &lt;span class="caps"&gt;8GB&lt;/span&gt;), and about 100 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GB&lt;/span&gt; of hard drive space. While &lt;span class="caps"&gt;2GB&lt;/span&gt; should be enough for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, I decided to give it more power as I anticipate running heavy queries in the future. And with that, we&amp;#8217;re good to kick off our&amp;nbsp;learning!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Learning Path"></category><category term="environment setup"></category></entry><entry><title>My First Post</title><link href="https://kishansampat.github.io/My-first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-14T00:23:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-14T00:23:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Kishan Sampat</name></author><id>tag:kishansampat.github.io,2020-05-14:/My-first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first&amp;nbsp;post&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first post! (took some tries)
- Adding edit to about page and test push 1 &lt;/br&gt;
- Adding edit to about page and test push 2 &lt;/br&gt;
- Adding edit to about page and test push 3 &lt;/br&gt;
- Adding edit to about page and test push 4 &lt;/br&gt;
- Adding edit to about page and test push 5 &lt;/br&gt;
- Adding edit to about page and test push 6 &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Misc"></category><category term="first"></category><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>